{"tossups": [{"question": "One man in this family was exiled to Venice after his city\u2019s failure to conquer Lucca and later exiled the Albizzi and Strozzi families on his return. Archbishop Francesco Salviati was executed for his role in one plot against a member of this family, which resulted in the death of Giulano, the Pazzi Conspiracy. That member of this family patronized Botticelli and was known as the Magnificent. Cosimo and Lorenzo were from, for ten points, what Florentine banking family?", "answer": "de<b> Medici</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Because Arthur Chilson and two associates sailed to Africa in 1902 to establish this religion, Kenya today has the most members of this religion. The acronym \u201cSPICES\u201d is used to remember principles in this religion. Members of this religion attend business gatherings called Yearly Meetings. Members of this religion believe in God as one\u2019s \u201cinner light.\u201d For ten points, name this religion, founded by George Fox and practiced by Richard Nixon, Mary Dyer, and William Penn.", "answer": "Religious Society of<b> Friends</b> (accept<b> Quakers</b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "During this man\u2019s governorship, James Rector was killed during \u201cBloody Thursday\u201d at People\u2019s Park. Though supposedly pro-life, this man signed a \u201cTherapeutic Abortion Act\u201d resulting in over 2 million abortions in his state. The Black Panthers protested this man\u2019s signing of the Mulford Act, and he was succeeded by Jerry Brown\u2019s first term. For 10 points, name this Republican governor of California and former actor who later defeated Jimmy Carter for President in 1980.", "answer": "Ronald<b> Reagan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event was investigated by Thomas Walsh after John McKendrick was tipped-off. A court case stemming from this event granted Congress the power to compel testimony.<em> McGrain v. Daugherty</em> grew out of this event during which Albert Fall became the first Cabinet member to be sent to jail. The leasing of Elk Hills in exchange for bribes was central to, for ten points, what oil scandal that rocked Warren G. Harding\u2019s presidency?", "answer": "<b> Teapot Dome</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Troops on this campaign stopped to aid Alfonso I in the capture of Moorish Lisbon, their only success in this campaign. This campaign culminated in a slaughter at a vineyard outside Damascus. Manuel Komnenos was accused of colluding with the Seljuk Turks against this campaign\u2019s leaders, Louis VII and Conrad III. After the County of Edessa fell to Zengi, Bernard of Clairvaux recruited soldiers for this campaign. For ten points, name this 1147 campaign called by Pope Eugene III.", "answer": "<b> Second Crusade</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Racial covenants on housing were found unconstitutional in a case originating in this city,<em> Shelley v.</em> <em>Kraemer</em>. The Eads Bridge in this city was the first bridge across the Mississippi south of the Missouri. This former location of the Pruitt-Igoe public housing projects is home to a weighted catenary designed by Eero Saarinen symbolizing its connection to the American West. For 10 points, name this Midwestern city home to the Gateway Arch.", "answer": "<b> St. Louis</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s aide, John Armstrong, was caught attempting to lead a military coup in the Newburgh Conspiracy. The Baron de Kalb died while under the command of this man as part of the disastrous Battle of Camden. The Conway Cabal aimed to replace George Washington with this man. This man claimed credit for defending the Bemis Heights from John Burgoyne which led to resentment from Benedict Arnold. For ten points, name this man who commanded American forces at Saratoga.", "answer": "Horatio<b> Gates</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Ulric Neisser studied the memory of a participant in this event, confidently declaring that that person\u2019s memory was not equal to a tape recorder. J. Fred Buzhardt was brought over from the Department of Defense during this event in order to investigate John Dean. During a Sam Ervin-led committee on this scandal, Howard Baker asked, \u201cWhat did the President know and when did he know it?\u201d A break-in at the headquarters of the Democratic National Committee sparked, for ten points, what scandal that ended Richard Nixon\u2019s presidency?", "answer": "<b> Watergate</b> scandal", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s Forward Party became the largest party in parliament in its first election in 2006. The Alignment Party is the only party ever to have formed a majority government in this country. This country\u2019s Labour Party dominated politics up until 1977 and is currently led by Avi Gabbay. In this country\u2019s 2019 elections, the Blue and White party led by Benny Gantz won 35 seats in the Knesset. For ten points, name this country currently led by the leader of the Likud Party, Benjamin Netanyahu.", "answer": "<b> Israel</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One leader with this name was strongly influenced by the Duke of Lerma. Another leader with this name married Elizabeth Farnese and was the first Bourbon leader of his country. The most famous leader with this name signed the Treaty of Joinville and annexed Portugal. That leader with this name was the son of Charles V and sent a large military force to defeat Elizabeth I. For ten points, give this name of five Spanish kings, including the monarch who dispatched the Spanish Armada.", "answer": "<b> Philip</b> (Accept<b> Philip III</b>, accept<b> Philip V</b>, accept<b> Philip II</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this South Asian country once known as East Pakistan.", "answer": "<b> Bangladesh</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>During the rule of this man, an anarchist rally was crushed in the Red Flag Incident which led to an assassination plot called the High Treason Incident two years later. In one</b> <b>document, this ruler promised to break off the (+)</b> <b>\u201cevil customs of the past\u201d and base</b> <b>everything on the \u201cjust laws of Nature.\u201d In 1895, this ruler\u2019s government began several policies under the slogan \u201cEnrich the country, (*)</b> strengthen the military.\u201d This ruler dismantled his country\u2019s domain system replacing it with a system of 72 prefectures. For ten points, name this Emperor of Japan who immediately began westernizing the country after seizing power in 1871.", "answer": "<b> Meiji</b> (accept<b> Mutsuhito</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>These locations were the focus of a John Collier-sponsored \u201cNew Deal\u201d which aimed to create, among other things, economic self-sufficiency. Starting in the 1940s, these locations were the target of a (+) \u201ctermination\u201d policy that unexempted them from federal and state taxes. A rock band named Coyote Springs is the subject of a Sherman Alexie novel named for the (*)</b> \u201cblues\u201d of these locations. The case<em> California v. Cabazon</em> ruled that these places can have gambling facilities as long as that type of gambling is legal within the state they are located. The Trail of Tears resulted in an increased number of, for ten points, what areas of land managed by Native American tribes?", "answer": "Indian<b> reservation</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One unnamed character in this work is given the name Musa in a response to this work that is told from the perspective of Musa\u2019s brother Harun and was written by Kamel (+) </b> <b>Daoud. The main character of this novel defends Raymond Sint\u00b4es\u2019 beating his girlfriend and angrily rejects God while in prison. That main character is sentenced to be executed after the fact that he (*) </b> failed to cry at his mother\u2019s funeral was used to show he felt no remorse for shooting an Arab on the beach. The Mersault Investigation was written in response to, for ten points, what existential novel by Albert Camus?", "answer": "The<b> Stranger</b> (accept<b> L\u2019\u00b4etranger</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A secret society consisting founded by members of this ethnicity was infiltrated by Franklin Gowen and attacked by the Coal and Iron Police. A religious divide among</b> <b>members of this ethnicity led to the 1871 (+)</b> <b>Orange Riots. By 1900, members</b> <b>of this ethnicity represented over 70% of New York police officers which led to the founding of the (*) </b> Emerald Society. The Molly Maguires were composed of, for ten points, what traditionally Catholic ethnic group that heavily settled New England?", "answer": "<b> Irish</b>-Americans", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}